<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="62"><page Index="1" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  Sectra Family 2020 Holiday Cookbook
 i
 ]]></page><page Index="2" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[                 ]]></page><page Index="3" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ In Loving Memory
of Doug Comer
“Share a kind word or act with all you meet, it’s free and it brightens the world.”
–Doug, 2017
Sectra Family Recipes
Apps & Soup 1
Sides & Sauces 9
Main Dishes 21
Desserts 39
Cocktails 55
Thank you to all contributors for sharing stories and recipes that are meaningful celebrations of family and friends.
    ]]></page><page Index="4" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[               1
  ]]></page><page Index="5" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Apps & Soup
2
]]></page><page Index="6" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Rye Bread Pizza by Paul McNamara
When my wife and I got married, Ingredients
  her family gave her a planner filled with recipes. Small, easy to make recipes for a new couple starting out.
Prep Time: 30 minutes Cook Time: 15 minutes Servings: 10-15
Utensils
– Cookie sheet
– Spoon
– Bowl
– Skillet/Frying Pan
– 1 lb. roll of medium to hot sausage
– 1 loaf of party rye bread – 1 lb. Velveeta cheese
– 1 Tbs of Ketchup
– 2 Tbs of Worcester sauce – Oregano
Directions
• Preheat oven to 400 degrees.
• Cook sausage in a skillet until brown and drain the grease.
• Melt in the Velveeta,
ketchup, and Worcester sauce in the same skillet with the sausage. Stir.
• Spread the desired amount onto each piece of party rye and place on a cookie sheet.
• Sprinkle with a little oregano.
• Place in oven and heat for approximately 12 minutes. Longer if you want to edges crispy.
  3
 ]]></page><page Index="7" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Jan’s Crabmeat Appetizers by Thomas Pacenta
These are great appetizers — Directions
 they taste great and are easy to make.
Ingredients
– 8 oz Butter
– 6 oz Jar Kraft Old
English Cheese Spread
– 1 1/2 tsp Mayonnaise
– 1 1/2 tsp garlic salt
– 8 oz Crabmeat
– 6 English muffins, split
• Have all ingredients at room temperature.
• Blend butter, cheese, mayo, garlic and crabmeat.
• Spread on muffins and place on cookie sheet.
• Freeze until solid. While frozen, cut into quarters and put in plastic bag to store in freezer until needed.
• To serve, heat under broiler for a few minutes, until slightly brown or bake at 400 degrees for 15–20 minutes.
   4
  ]]></page><page Index="8" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  Maine Lobster Stew
by Brian Maynard
My family is from Maine, so I spent a lot of time there as a child visiting relatives on Mt. Desert Island, and Lobster Stew was one of my favorites there.
Ingredients Directions
• Add the hot milk/cream mixture and the lobster.
• Season with paprika & dill to taste. Can also add pepper and salt if you wish.
• Add sherry, 3⁄4 to 1 cup is my preference.
• Bring to a boil and then immediately reduce heat to a simmer.
• Simmer covered for 30-45 minutes, but avoid going too long (more than an hour) or the potatoes and lobster may get a bit mushy.
  – 1 pound lobster meat (frozen mixed meat, tails and claws, is usually the least expensive option and is fine for this. No real advantage to fresh)
– 3-5 small potatoes (I use red bliss and I don’t peel them) chopped.
– 2 Tbsp. butter (a good starting point, but add as needed)
– 2 cups light cream
– 2 cups milk
– 1 onion
– Garlic
– Dry Sherry (optional, but not as far as I’m concerned). You can also add sherry to individual servings.
• Place the 2 cups of light cream
and 2 cups of milk in a pan and slowly heat to avoid curdling. Heat until hot to the touch.
• While the cream/milk is heating, dice the potatoes and onions, and clean and cut up the lobster. Cut the lobster to the size you prefer in the stew.
• Using the pan you will cook the stew in, take some butter and garlic and cook for a minute or two in the bottom of the pan. Add the onions and cook them until they start to sweat, 3-5 minutes.
• Add the potatoes to lightly sear/fry and absorb the other flavors, 5 minutes
or so. When you are cooking, you may want to add some additional butter to aid in the cooking process.
5
 ]]></page><page Index="9" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Taco Soup by Jill Reed-Ybarra A go-to Winter soup!
Ingredients
– 1 lb. lean ground beef
– 1 onion, chopped
– 3 cans (15 1⁄2 oz each) chili beans, undrained
– 1 can (14 1⁄2 oz) whole tomatoes, undrained
– 1 can (14 1⁄4 oz) corn, undrained
– 1 can (8 oz) tomato sauce
– 1 pkg taco seasoning mix
– 1 1⁄2 c water
– 1 1⁄2 c shredded cheddar cheese
Directions
• Brown beef with onions in large saucepan and drain.
• Add all remaining ingredients except cheese.
• Stir, breaking up tomatoes.
• Bring to a boil.
• Simmer on medium-low heat 5 minutes, stirring occasionally.
• Top with cheese.
• Note, you may also add all ingredients (except cheese) in Crockpot and cook on low for 4-5 hours.
        6
  ]]></page><page Index="10" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Mushroom Soup by Tracy Rigo
This is a favorite with all of my family and because of the rich nature of the soup is only served on special occasions. I am afraid I can’t remember where I got this recipe, but I think everyone will enjoy it.
A luscious soup that can be made a head of time and assembled when ready to serve.
Ingredients Directions
– 1⁄2 C minced onion
– 1⁄2 C unsalted butter, divided
– 6 TAP flour
– 12C homemade chicken stock or low-sodium canned broth
– 2 springs fresh parsley leaves, plus more for garnish
– 1 small dried bay leaf – Pinch dried thyme
– Juice of 1⁄2 lemon
– 4 Large egg yolks
– 1 C heavy cream
– 3 pounds various mushrooms (Cremini, Oyster, Shiitake, etc.) cleaned, trimmed, and sliced
– Coarse salt
• Cook onions in 4 tablespoons butter in a large stockpot over medium heat until soft, 4 to 5 minutes. Stir in flour and cook over low heat for 4 minutes without browning. Add the stock, blending it completely with the flour. Add the parsley, bay leaf, and thyme, and simmer for 20 minutes. Strain into a second pot.
• In a large skillet, heat remaining 4 tablespoons butter over medium
heat. Add the cremini mushrooms and season with salt. Cook until softened, and then add the shiitake and oyster mushrooms. Season with salt and lemon juice and cook until mushrooms are deep golden brown, 8 to 10 minutes. At this point you can stop and store the ingredients and assemble close to dinner.
• Reheat stock mixture to a simmer. Whisk the egg yolks and cream until blended. While whisking, slowly add a cupful of the hot soup into the cream mixture and add back to the soup and heat to just below a simmer (if the soup simmers, the yolks will curdle). Add the cooked mushroom mixture and stir to combine. Serve garnished with parsley.
 7
 ]]></page><page Index="11" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  8
  ]]></page><page Index="12" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[                 9
 ]]></page><page Index="13" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Sides & Sauces
10
]]></page><page Index="14" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Swiss Chard Made Simple by Mina Lawrence
During my childhood days, my Mom often made different kinds of leafy green vegetables to accompany the main dish served during dinner. The greens were cooked very simply with just garlic to neutralize the rich flavors of the main dish. This very basic and simple swiss chard recipe was inspired by my Mom who taught me the basics of cooking healthy nutritious meals.
Swiss Chard can be found in most grocery stores and is packed with valuable nutrients. This is a very healthy dish and simple to make. An excellent side dish to your main course.
Ingredients Directions
 – Swiss Chard
– 2 tbsp olive oil
– 2-3 cloves garlic finely chopped
– Salt to taste
– 1⁄2 tsp cooking wine
• Wash the Swiss Chard thoroughly and cut into small pieces
• Heat 2 tbsp olive oil on medium heat.
• Sautee the garlic for 2 minutes
• Add Swiss Chard and stir to coat it with the garlic and oil
• Add salt and stir
• Cover and let it cook with the juices from the chard.
• After 3 minutes, check and see if the stems of the chard are soft.
• Add cooking wine and stir for 1 minute
• Serve.
  11
 ]]></page><page Index="15" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Baked Mushrooms by Michele Lynett This is a recipe that my mother Directions
  has made for years. Ingredients
– 1 1/2 lbs mushrooms
– 1/2 cup butter
– 1/2 cup finely chopped onion
– 1 clove garlic, crushed
– 1 cup bread crumbs (I use Italian crumbs)
– 1 cup heavy cream
– 2 eggs
– 1/2 tsp thyme (leaf crushed or regular)
– 1 tsp salt
– Freshly ground peppercorn
• Wash mushrooms under running water. Do not soak. Chop very coarsely.
• Melt butter in heavy skillet and sauté onion & garlic.
• Add mushrooms & toss lightly but do not cook.
• Add bread crumbs and toss again. Remove from heat.
• Mix eggs and cream together, add seasonings and mix with mushroo
• Pour into a buttered oven-proof dish and bake at 350 for 45-60 minutes until browned and set.
• Cool slightly before serving. Garnish with fresh parsley
 12
  ms.
  ]]></page><page Index="16" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Corn Casserole by Todd Vesco Cook time: 35 Min Directions
 Prep time: 5 Min Ingredients
– One can cream-style corn
– 1 c Bisquick mix
– One egg-well beaten
– 4 oz can(s) chopped green chilis
– 8 oz cheese-shredded
– 1/2 c milk
– 2 Tbsp sugar
– Black & red pepper to taste
– 1 Tbsp margarine
• Preheat oven to 375
• In a bowl: Mix corn, Bisquick mix, egg, milk, sugar, black pepper, red pepper, and margarine.
• In a casserole dish, layer half the batter, half the chilies, and half the cheese. Repeat.
• Bake in 375-degree oven for 35-40 minutes.
  13
 ]]></page><page Index="17" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Fresh Cranberry Sauce by Richard Chiappone Ingredients Directions
   – 1 bag Fresh Cranberries
– 1 1⁄4 cups Port Wine
– 1 1⁄2 cups Granulated Sugar
– 4 1⁄2 tsp Cornstarch
– 1⁄4 cup Cold Water
– 1⁄4 tsp Ground Cloves
• Place cranberries, sugar and
port wine in a 1 quart saucepan and bring to a boil.
• Once boiling, lower heat to simmer. Cover with splatter-screen. Berries should begin to pop.
• Occasionally stir as berries continue to pop.
• Add Ground Cloves.
• Once berries have popped and you have the consistency of chunky soup, gradually add cornstarch to the 1⁄4 cup water in a separate bowl. Do this while stirring until you have a milky liquid without chunks.
• Slowly add cornstarch to the simmering sauce pan with berries while stirring to thicken the mixture. Mix until smooth.
• Continue to simmer mixture and stir often while it continues to thicken to desired consistency.
• Remove from heat and place in bowl to cool.
• Once cool, cover and place in refrigerator overnight.
 14
  ]]></page><page Index="18" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Whiskey Cream Sauce by Michael Powell
Everything is better with a Directions
   15
great sauce.
Perfect over grilled steaks.
Ingredients
– 4 Tablespoons butter
– 1/2 Cup Whiskey
– 1/2 Cup of beef stock
– 1/2 Cup heavy whipping cream
– 1/2 Cup finely diced onions
– 1/2 Teaspoon salt
– Dash fresh ground pepper
• Cook the onions in the 3 tablespoons butter in a skillet over medium heat for a few minutes. When the onions are brown, turn off the burner before you add the whiskey.
• Pour in the whiskey. As soon
as it evaporates, turn the burner
on medium-high heat and pour in the beef stock. Add salt and freshly ground black pepper to taste, then allow
the mixture to bubble up and
reduce by half.
• Whisk in the remaining tablespoon
of butter, then reduce the heat to low. Whisk in 1/4 cup to 1/2 cup cream, according to your taste. Allow the sauce to simmer and thicken
for a few minutes.
• Place directly on your steaks and enjoy.
  ]]></page><page Index="19" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Le Grand Cran AKA Cranberry Sauce
by Sarah Hannah
The first Thanksgiving dinner Ingredients
  I had ever made I was determined to make from scratch right down to the cranberry sauce. Someone drank all the orange juice I needed so I did what I do on nearly every recipe—improvised. This recipe was born and loved and demanded each year after that. Enjoy!
– 2 bags Fresh Cranberries
– 1⁄2 cup White Sugar
– 1⁄2 cup Raw Sugar
– 4-5 Juiced Clementine Oranges – 1 nip Grand Marnier
Directions
• Combine all but cranberries in a medium saucepan on med-low heat until sugars are mostly dissolved.
• Add cranberries and increase temp to medium. Stir frequently so the sugars do not burn until most of the berries pop.
• Let cool and refrigerate overnight.
   16
  ]]></page><page Index="20" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Perfect Roast Potatoes by Joanna Proctor
Roast potatoes are the foundation of every celebratory British Utensils
 meal! Perfect roasties are hard to come by and this is how my family makes them.
These roast potatoes can be what you make them, they don’t
have to exactly follow this recipe, and can substitute any herbs and spices for those that you would prefer. Traditionally these would be made with goose fat and fresh rosemary and garlic, but
I love experimenting with other flavors too! One I really like is fresh rosemary, old bay seasoning, cayenne pepper, paprika and garlic powder. I love preparing these alongside roasted parsnips and carrots too, which pair really well with roasted potatoes in a “roast dinner” a traditional British Sunday dinner.
– Large roasting tin/baking dish
– Large saucepan (may need two) – Potato peeler
– Strainer
– Metal spoon
– Sharp knife and chopping board
Ingredients
– 2 lb potatoes (russet/Yukon gold work well, or any kind you prefer! Smaller varieties may need less time)
– Oil/goose fat/duck fat (whichever you prefer!)
– Fresh rosemary (or whichever herb you would like)
– 1 bulb of garlic, keep the cloves whole
– Salt and pepper
– Any dried herbs/spices you want to add e.g. old bay, garlic powder etc.
  17
 ]]></page><page Index="21" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  Directions
• Preheat the oven to 450 degrees Fahrenheit.
• Start by peeling and chopping the potatoes into chunks, the bigger they are the longer you will have to par-boil them, the smaller they are, the crispier they will be but may overcook easily. I like cutting my potatoes into quarters and find that size works well for me.
• Heavily (more than you think) salt a boiling saucepan of water before adding in your potatoes.
• Put a few glugs of oil or your
fat into your roasting tin/dish, adding the garlic and fresh herbs. If using a tin, place on a medium heat. If using a baking dish, place in the oven while potatoes are boiling.
• After 12-15 minutes remove potatoes from the pan, draining in the strainer before returning to the pan.
• Using the metal spoon, rough up the potatoes (not so they disintegrate), giving them more surface area. More surface area = crispier potatoes.
• Place potatoes (carefully) into dish, ensuring they are covered completely by the fat.
• Season with salt, pepper, and whichever else you would like!
• Place in the oven for 40-60 minutes, turning every 15 minutes or so, to ensure all sides are crispy. Keep checking on them!
• Serve alongside anything for a perfect potato side dish, goes very well with gravy on top!
•
 18
  ]]></page><page Index="22" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  Smashed Brussels Sprouts
by Anders Osterholm
Ingredients
– 2 lb. Brussels sprouts
– 2 tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil
– 4 cloves garlic, minced
– 1 tsp. freshly chopped thyme
– Kosher salt
– Freshly ground black pepper
– 1 cup freshly grated Parmesan
Directions
• Preheat oven to 425 degrees
• Add sprouts to boiling water and let cook for about 10 minutes
• Toss sprouts, oil, garlic and thyme in a cooking dish
• Smash them with a bottle or jar
• Season with salt and pepper
• Sprinkle Parmesan on top
• Bake in oven for about 20 minutes
 19
 ]]></page><page Index="23" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  Crockpot Stuffing
by Jill Reed-Ybarra
Great for Thanksgiving! Directions
  Ingredients
– 1⁄2 c butter
– 1 c chopped walnuts
– 2 onions chopped
– 14 oz pkg cubed herbed seasoned stuffing
– 1 1⁄2 c applesauce
– 1 c water
– Dried cranberries (optional)
• In large skillet, melt 2 tbsp butter and cook walnuts over medium heat until toasted and fragrant (about 5 min).
• Remove nuts and set aside in bowl.
• Melt remaining 6 tbsp butter in the same skillet and add onion and cook 3-4 minutes until almost tender.
• Spray 4-6 quart slow cooker with nonstick spray and place stuffing cubes in prepared Crockpot.
• Add cooked onion with butter and mix gently.
• Add applesauce and water and mix lightly. Cover and cook on low 4-5 hours.
• Sprinkle top with toasted walnuts before serving.
• Optionally, you may add dried cranberries in the mix and on top.
• Makes ten 3⁄4 c servings. Doubling the recipe is great for family gatherings.
 20
  ]]></page><page Index="24" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[              21
  ]]></page><page Index="25" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Main Dishes
22
]]></page><page Index="26" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Cheesy Hash Brown Casserole by Paul McNamara
 This recipe is different
from your typical breakfast food. It’s been passed though my wife’s family.
Prep Time: 30 minutes Cook Time: 1 hour Servings: 4
Ingredients Directions
– 2 lbs. of hamburger
– 1 small yellow onion (chopped)
– 1 can cream of mushroom soup
– 1 cup shredded cheddar cheese
– 3 cups shredded frozen hash browns
– Salt and pepper to taste
Utensils
• 1 1⁄2 quart casserole dish
• Spoon
• Skillet/Frying Pan
• Preheat the over to 375 degrees.
• Brown hamburger, drain fat.
• Add onion and cook until tender.
• Remove from heat and add soup.
• In a lightly greased 1 1⁄2 quart casserole dish, add the frozen hash browns.
• Sprinkle the cheese on the hash browns.
• Top with the meat mixture. • Bake at 375 for 1 hour.
• Remove from oven.
 23
 ]]></page><page Index="27" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[   24
  ]]></page><page Index="28" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Swedish Cabbage Casserole by Anders & Petra Granlund
This is one of the most traditional Swedish dishes, that’s been around for ages. It’s a very common dish at Swedish restaurants and something we brought to the International Lunch Day in Shelton while living in the U.S. This particular recipe is from one of the most famous Swedish chefs (no, not the one in the Muppet Show :),
Leif Mannerstrom.
Ingredients
– 1.6 kg minced meat (original recipe uses 50% pork, 50% beef blend)
– 2 tablespoons brown sugar – 4 tablespoons butter,
melted for brushing
– 4 tablespoons veal stock, concentrated
– 4 tbsp syrup (not maple, neutral – can be sub with other neutral sweet syrup, e.g. agave)
– 12 tablespoons Japanese soy sauce
– 4 eggs
– .8 cups of breadcrumbs (not seasoned)
– 1.6 cups milk (regular whole)
– 2 potatoes, boiled, cold
– Butter, for frying and form (about a stick)
– 2 yellow onions (small, not the onion ring sized)
– 2 med sized cabbage heads (fresh green or savoy)
– Salt and pepper
For serving
– Gravy
– 1 qt heavy cream
– 2-3 bouillon cubes, preferably Knorr – beef flavor
– Add the liquid from casserole when it’s been baked
– Salt and pepper to taste
– Lingonberry jam (IKEA has it)
Pickled cucumber
– 1 fresh cucumber thinly sliced – Pinch of salt
– 2 tsp sugar
– 2 tsp white vinegar
– 1/3 cup of water
– 2 tsp chopped parsley
• Mix and let rest for a few hours in the refrigerator before serving
  25
 ]]></page><page Index="29" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[   Cabbage Casserole
• Cut out the stem of the cabbage
head. Pre-boil cabbage head in lightly salted water for 10-15 minutes (the longer time for green cabbage,
shorter for savoy).
• Pick up cabbage with a slotted spoon and carefully loosen the fine leaves. Cut off the middle nerve on each leaf and set the leaves aside. Save the cabbage you cut away.
• Peel and finely chop the onions. Finely chop the cabbage leftovers and fry with the onion and some butter. Mash the cold potatoes with a fork. Mix cabbage/ onion blend and mashed potatoes with milk and breadcrumbs.
• Let rest (swell) for 10 minutes and then add minced meat, eggs, soy, syrup and veal stock. Add salt and pepper. Stir quickly to a smooth batter. Important! Fry a tablespoon sample to taste and adjust the seasoning if needed, this dish needs salt/umami from stock.
•
Set the oven to 390 °F. Quickly fry the cabbage leaves in butter. Build layer
on layer of cabbage leaves and minced meat batter in a greased oven solid form, finish with cabbage leaves on top. Brush with melted butter, add fresh ground pepper and a pinch of salt and brown sugar on top.
Bake in the middle of the oven for 40-45 minutes, adding an oven plate/cookie sheet under may be a good idea in case of overflow. The liquid released when baking the casserole can be added to the gravy (see above).
Serve immediately with boiled potatoes, gravy, pickled cucumber and lingonberry jam.
•
•
26
  ]]></page><page Index="30" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  Turkey Keema by Mina Lawrence
This recipe was inspired by my Ingredients
   husband’s family. They would often make this dish with beef and take it to a picnic to make sandwiches. I prefer turkey over beef and sometimes I would add green peas, lima beans or potatoes. This recipe is a staple, it is fairly easy to whip up in a large batch on a weekend. A good source of protein which can accompany most carbs. It is an easy prep for pot lucks too.
If you are the type who likes more flavor in your meat, this may be the dish for you. This can be eaten with rice, naan bread (flat Indian bread – ShopRite has it), used as a stuffing for bell peppers, pastry and even use it in a sandwich.
– 1 tray of ground turkey
– 1 large onion chopped
– 4-5 gloves of garlic finely chopped
– 3 curry leaves (optional)
– 2-3 dried red peppers
– 2 tsp fenugreek seeds
– 2 tsp turmeric powder
– 3 tsp black pepper
– 1⁄2 cup of sweet green peas or lima beans
– Salt to taste Directions
• Heat 1-2 tbsp of olive oil
• Break the dried red peppers
into halves and drop them in the oil with the curry leaves
• Add the onion and garlic
• Sauté until onions are translucent
• Add the ground meat
• Season with turmeric powder, black pepper and salt. Mix well
• You’ll have to keep mixing to prevent the meat from becoming a lump
• When the meat is no longer pink, add the fenugreek seeds and salt
• Add the green peas
(you can add frozen peas)
• Keep stirring the meat until it is well cooked and loose.
• Remove from pan and serve
27
 ]]></page><page Index="31" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Sausage & Peppers by Richard Chiappone
Here’s one of my faves for the table. Not my original recipe, I found it somewhere at some point. But it’s a simple one to throw in between other items when you’re in cooking mode.
Ingredients Directions
  – 2lbs Italian Sweet or Hot Sausage (cut into bite-size chunks)
– 1- 8oz Can of Tomato Sauce
– 3-4 Tablespoons Garlic Powder
– 1 Tbsp Oregano
– 1 Tbsp Diced Fresh Parsley
– 5-10 Green (or Red, or both) Bell Peppers (destem and pits removed-cut into strips)
– 1 Medium Size White Onion, cut into thin strips
– Olive Oil
– Optional: Italian Grinder Rolls-sliced open for sandwiches
• Preheat oven to 400 degrees
• Spray a large roasting pan with nonstick cooking spray
• Place peppers, onions, sausage
• Sprinkle salt, garlic powder, oregano and parsley evenly over all
• Drizzle Olive Oil evenly over all • Place on middle rack in oven
• Bake for 1⁄2 hour uncovered
• Add 8oz can of Tomato Sauce and stir into the whole pan of ingredients
• Bake for an additional 1⁄2 hour
• Serve with Grinder rolls on the side
 28
  ]]></page><page Index="32" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Vegetarian Swedish Meatballs by James Poehlmann
My wife is a vegetarian and I like it.
Ingredients for Meatballs
– 1 medium yellow onion, finely minced
– 2 tablespoons Earth Balance
– 2/3 cups cashew cream or plain soy creamer
– 3 slices of bread, crusts cut off, and cubed
– 1 package beyond meat crumbles, thawed
– 1 package gimme Lean Sausage Style
– 2 teaspoons sea salt
– 1⁄2 teaspoon nutmeg
– 1⁄2 teaspoon cardamom
– 1 teaspoon black pepper
Ingredients for Sauce
– Tablespoons earth balance
– 1/3 cup unbleached flour
– 1 quart veggie chicken stock or plain veggie stock with a tablespoon of poultry seasoning added
– 12 ounces vegan sour cream, or to taste
– Sea salt, to taste
– 1 cup cremini mushrooms, sliced thin – 1⁄4 cup dry sherry (optional)
Directions
• Sauté the finely diced onion in 2 tablespoons Earth Balance over medium high heat until soft. Remove and allow to cool.
• In a mixing bowl, mix the bread cubes with the cashew cream, only adding a bit of the cream (or soy cream) at a time until the bread becomes moist, not saucy. Set aside for about 10 minutes or so.
• Add the onions to the bread mixture along with all of the remaining ingredients and seasonings for the meatballs. Simply pinch off and round each meatball with your hands. Try and keep them somewhat uniform. Apply medium pressure with balling so they will not break apart while cooking.
• Heat 6 tablespoons of Earth Balance
in a large sauté pan over medium heat. When the butter has melted, start browning your meatballs. DO NOT CROWD! Do the browning in batches. Use care when turning them so they do not fall apart. Sing to them. Tell them how lovely they are.
• Remove each batch as the are browned on all sides.
• Use a slotted spoon to remove them
as you want to keep the butter and drippings in the pan for the sauce. You may have to add more butter if most is gone or if it tastes burnt. You want to keep the equivalent of 6 tablespoons of butter in the pan.
29
 ]]></page><page Index="33" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  • Slowly whisk in your flour. Stir constantly until it looks like a golden caramel color. Remove from heat.
• Heat your veggie stock. Once it has a light steam to it, replace your butter/flour to the burner and whisk in the veggie stock. Stir constantly. Add in your mushrooms and keep whisking. Reduce the heat and add your meatballs. Cover and simmer until the sauce thickens. If it thickens too much, add a bit of creamer or veg stock by whisking. Keep an eye on it.
• Turn your meatballs, grab your dry sherry and splash some in while whisking vigorously. Can you smell it? Yum! Now remove from the heat once the gravy is the thickness you desire.
• Using a slotted spoon, remove the balls and plate
them over your pasta or rice. Add the vegan sour cream while still whisking vigorously.
• Once well blended and gorgeous, ladle over the meat balls and serve with style and grace to your friends or family. I like to top mine with just a whisper of chopped cilantro and some Lingonberry sauce on the side.
  30
  ]]></page><page Index="34" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[   Bolognese by Stefan Melin Ingredients Directions
 – 1 kg of minced beef meat
– 2 large onions, finely chopped
– 2 carrots, finely grated
– 1 cube of veal broth
– 1 cube of chicken broth
– 1.5 dl of sun dried tomatoes, finely chopped
– 2 pieces of garlic
– 3 table spoons of soy
– 750 g (1 jar) of crushed tomatoes
– 2 table spoons of tomato purée
– 2 dl of cream (NOTE! the real deal, not some light product...)
– 1⁄2 dl of oregano
– Salt, if needed
– Pepper
– Cayenne pepper
– Curry
• Take out a large frying pan and
start frying the minced meat together with the onions and the carrots. After a while, add the cubes of broth and let them use the liquid in the frying pan to mix well with the meat, onions
and carrots.
• When most of the liquid has boiled away, add the soy, the garlic and the sun dried tomatoes. Let it simmer for about 5 minutes while stirring thoroughly to mix all ingredients.
• When you feel like it, add the crushed tomatoes and the tomato purée, stir again to that everything mixes and let it simmer for another 5 minutes.
• Add the cream, stir thoroughly and let the sauce simmer until the texture is perfect.
• Add the oregano, pepper, salt if needed and top it off with the cayenne pepper and the curry. NOTE! The curry is only to enhance the total flavor of the dish, be careful not to add to much curry so
•
that you get a meat sauce that
tastes like something from the cuisine of India. If you are uncertain, skip the curry altogether.
Serve the meat sauce with spaghetti of good quality and add some grated Parmesan for extra luxury.
 31
 ]]></page><page Index="35" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  32
  ]]></page><page Index="36" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Sweet Pepper & Pancetta Frittata by Brittany Santella
For those who love brunch as much as I do, this recipe is a must-try. My friends and I love to get together and catch up over some good food and drinks and this recipe has now been
a staple item for these get togethers.
Serving Size: 4-6 Prep: 15 minutes Cook: 30 minutes
Ingredients Directions
– 8 ounces pancetta, finely chopped
– 1 tablespoon salted butter (if needed)
– 2 red, yellow, and/or orange bell peppers, cut into 1⁄2-inch dice
– 8 large eggs
– 1⁄4 cup heavy cream
– 2 teaspoons fresh thyme leaves or 1 teaspoon dried
– Kosher salt and fresh ground black pepper
– 4 ounces Gruyere cheese, grated (about 1 cup)
– 1⁄2 cup crumbled feta cheese (about 2 ounces)
– 2 cups baby arugula (about 2 ounces) – 2 teaspoons extra virgin olive oil
• Preheat oven to 375 degrees. Line a large bowl with paper towels and set aside.
• In a 10-inch nonstick oven-proof skillet or well-seasoned cast-iron skillet,
cook the pancetta over medium-high heat until browned and crisp (about 4 minutes), stirring occasionally. If there is little to no fat left in the pan, add the butter and heat up until melted. Add the bell peppers and cook until tender (about 4 minutes), stirring often. Scrape the mixture into the lined bowl to drain off the extra grease.
• Wipe out the skillet and place it over medium-low heat. Return the pancetta and pepper mixture to the skillet.
• In a medium bowl, vigorously whisk the eggs, cream, thyme, 1 teaspoon salt, and 1⁄2 teaspoon pepper until well combined. Stir in the Gruyere.
• Pour the egg mixture evenly into the skilled. Gently shake the pan from time to time to ensure the eggs are not
   33
 ]]></page><page Index="37" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[   sticking or scorching on the bottom, and when the edges of the frittata are firm, lift them up with a spatula and gently tilt the pan so that the uncooked egg can run underneath. Cook until the eggs are set and golden on the bottom and sides (about 3 minutes).
• Transfer to the oven to bake until the eggs are nearly set but still moist on top (about 10 minutes). Remove the pan from the oven and crumble the feta cheese on top of the frittata.
• Turn the broiler to high. Place the pan under the broiler until the eggs are just set and the cheese is soft, warm, and browned in a few spots (about 3 minutes).
• In a medium bowl, toss the arugula with the oil and season to taste with salt and pepper. Cut the frittata into wedges, top with arugula, and serve warm.
• Store leftovers in a covered container in the refrigerator for up to 2 days.
34
  ]]></page><page Index="38" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Kluski (Noodles) Paczki (Donuts) and Babka (Bread) Apricot Kielbasa by Kathy Hoffmann
 SMACZNEGO
(In English = Enjoy your meal)
Grandma was watched by my Aunt Virginia and measured as they went along.
Like many immigrants Grandma spoke but did not read or write English.
Kloski Ingredients
– 1⁄2 tsp salt
– 2 cups flour
– Water – enough so that you can drop from a spoon into boiling water.
Directions
• Boil about 1 minute till clusters come up to the surface of the water.
• Remove and drain.
Paczki Ingredients
– 4 cups flour
– 2 or 3 eggs
– 1⁄2 cup butter or margarine
– 1 cup sugar
– 1 or 1 1⁄2 cups milk. Use judgement. – 1 tsp salt
– 2 dry yeast
Directions
• Melt yeast first in the 1⁄2 cup luke-warm water
• Beat eggs in separate bowl.
• Warm milk, butter and sugar together till luke-warm
• Pour this and eggs and yeast into flour.
• Work by hand or wooden spoon till dough no longer sticks.
• Let rise in warm place 2, 3 or
4 hours until amount of dough had in beginning doubles.
• Deep fry in boiling lard or oil until golden brown.
Babka Bread Ingredients
– Use same dough as for paczki but add raisins.
– After working in bowl, work some more on floured table surface.
– Half-fill pans and allow to rise in them. – Place crumbs on top.
Directions
• Preheat oven 15 minutes. Bake at 3:30 degrees about 3⁄4 hour.
Crumbs for Babka Bread
– 1⁄2 cup sugar
– 1⁄2 cup flour
– 1 tbsp lard or butter – 1 pinch salt
• Work until crumbly
 35
 ]]></page><page Index="39" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[    Apricot Kielbasa Ingredients
– 1 pound fully cooked kielbasa or Polish sausage cut into 1/4-inch slices
– 1 jar 12 ounces apricot preserves
– 2 tablespoons lemon juice
– 2 teaspoons Dijon mustard
– 1/4 teaspoon ground ginger
Directions
• Brown kielbasa on both sides in skillet. Add remaining ingredients to skillet and heat through over low heat until apricot preserves melt. Stir often.
36
  ]]></page><page Index="40" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  Pecan Pancakes with Maple Butter
by Brittany Santella
  For the pancake lovers, I hope you enjoy this recipe are much as we do. We try to make pancakes at least once a week and these are our go-to. Some of the best (and even craziest with two under 4) memories are made at the table.
Serving Size: 4 Prep: 15 minutes Cook: 20 minutes
Ingredients
– 1 cup pecans
– 2 cups all-purpose flower
– 1⁄4 cup granulated sugar
– 1 1⁄2 teaspoons baking powder
– 1 1⁄2 teaspoons baking soda
– 1 teaspoon kosher salt
– 2 1⁄2 cups buttermilk
– 2 large eggs, separated
– 1 teaspoon pure vanilla extract
– 2 tablespoons unsalted butter, melted – Maple butter
– Maple syrup, for serving
Directions
• Preheat the oven to 250 degrees F. Set a wire rack on a sheet pan.
• In a large dry skillet, toast the pecans over medium-high heat, stirring constantly, until fragrant, 3 to 5 minutes. Remove from the pan and let cool completely. Coarsely chop and set aside.
• In a large bowl, whisk together the flour, sugar, baking powder, baking soda,
and salt. Make a well in the center.
Pour the buttermilk and egg yolks into the well and whisk by hand until just incorporated (there will be lumps). Add the vanilla and melted butter and stir gently until incorporated. Do not over whisk (the batter can be refrigerated for up to 1 hour).
• Just before cooking the pancakes,
in a large bowl, with an electric mixer, beat the egg whites until soft peaks form, about 1 minute. Fold gently into the better.
• Heat a large nonstick griddle to
300 degrees F or a nonstick skillet over medium-low heat for about 5 minutes.
• Working in batches to avoid overcrowding, user a measuring cup
to ladle 1/3 cup batter onto the griddle or skillet for each pancake. Cook until the pancakes begin to bubble in the middle and the bottom edges brown (about 2-4 minutes). Flip the pancakes and cook until the other side is slightly browned, 1 to 2 minutes more. Transfer each batch of pancakes to the wire track and place them in the oven to keep warm until ready to serve.
• Stack the pancakes, top with pats of maple butter, and sprinkle with the toasted pecans. Pour your favorite maple syrup over the top and serve.
• Store in an airtight container in the refrigerator overnight.
37
 ]]></page><page Index="41" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Maple Butter Serving Size: 1 cup Prep: 10 minutes, plus 20 minutes chilling
Ingredients
– 1 cup (2 sticks) unsalted butter, at room temperature
– 1/3 cup plus 2 tablespoons of maple syrup
– 1⁄2 teaspoon kosher salt Directions
• In a stand mixer fitted with the whisk, beat the butter on high speed until light and fluffy (about 4 minutes). Turn the speed to low and slowly pour in the syrup. Mix until well incorporated. Add the salt, turn the speed to high, and beat for 2 minutes, stopped to scrape down the bowl halfway through.
• Scrape the butter onto parchment paper and roll into a log. Twist the ends of the parchment paper to secure and refrigerate for 20 minutes.
• Unwrap the log and slice the butter into pats when ready to serve.
• Store in an airtight container in the refrigerator for up to 7 days on in the freezer for up to 1 month.
  38
  ]]></page><page Index="42" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[                    39
 ]]></page><page Index="43" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Desserts
40
]]></page><page Index="44" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Italian Biscotti by Richard Chiappone Ingredients Directions
– 3 1⁄2 cups unsifted all-purpose flour
– 1 cup chopped nuts (we use a combination of hazel nuts and pistachios—you use whatever the hell you like)
– 1⁄4 tsp baking soda
– 1⁄4 tsp salt
– 3 large eggs
– 1 1⁄2 cups granulated sugar
– 1⁄2 cup butter (melted)
– 1⁄2 tsp Anise extract (or vanilla for all you Ameri-gans!)
– Option: 1⁄4 cup Powdered sugar
• Preheat Oven to 350 degrees
• Grease a large baking sheet, set aside (“use a zip lock bag as a glove to do that, not your damn hands!”...so much for helping....)
• In a medium mixing bowl, combine flour, nuts, baking soda, and salt. Set aside.
• In a large mixing bowl, use mixer on medium speed to beat eggs together with sugar, butter and extract until well blended.
• Using spatula (or Julia’s mother’s wooden spoon with the chip in the end from throwing it), gradually stir in the flour mixture.
• Now, change to dough hooks if you have them. (If not, be prepared to work harder!)
• Knead the mixture with machine or your hands until the mixture forms a stiff dough ball.
• Divide the dough in half
• Shape each half onto a 12”x2” roll, then flatten just a bit (Does that look like a bit?! Do it again the right way now!...That was her mother from the peanut gallery...can’t win)
• Place each half on the baking sheet, approx. 5” apart
• Bake on center rack at 350 degrees for 30 mins. or until the (somewhat flattened!) rolls are firm and very lightly browned
• Remove from the oven and gently transfer each roll to a cutting board, making sure NOT to break the roll apart.
• Cut each roll into 1” slices using diagonal cuts
• Place slices back onto baking sheet with the CUT SIDE down. (that would be sideways, you know, on its side!)
• Place back into 350 degree oven for an additional 7-8 mins until firm. • Remove from oven and cool.
• When cool, sprinkle lightly with powdered sugar as an option.
• (Anyone who says they don’t like ‘em after all that work gets banished to the basement for the rest of the night! You can also forget getting invited back next holiday)
  41
 ]]></page><page Index="45" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  Schnecken (German Snail Cookies)
by Kenneth Eschrich
These are an Eschrich favorite Directions
 from Germany (especially when made by Grandma Schmitt!) Typically served with coffee as part of Frühstück (breakfast).
Ingredients
– 3 cup flour
– 8 oz butter
– 3 egg yolks
– 1⁄4 cup milk
– 1 cup heavy cream
– 2 1⁄4 teaspoon dry yeast
– 1 cup chopped nuts
– 1 1⁄2 cup sugar
– 2 1⁄2 teaspoon cinnamon
• Mix flour and butter until well blended
• Mix yolks, milk, and heavy cream and add to flour/butter
• Add in yeast
• Divide dough into 6
parts, wrapping each in foil
• Refrigerate dough overnight
• Roll each package into a circle on a floured board
• Divide nute/sugar/cinnamon mixture in 6
• Cover each dough on both sides with mixture
• Cut each circle in 8 wedges like a pie
• Roll up each wedge starting at wide end
• Bake on greased cookie sheet at 325 degrees for 25 minutes
   42
  ]]></page><page Index="46" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Blue Willow’s Peach Cobbler by Evita Summers
This was one of my late husband’s favorite dessert, especially with a heaping scoop of vanilla ice cream. Perfect for the holidays or any day!
Tools/Utensils Needed:
– Medium size mixing bowl
– Mixing Spoon
– Baking Dish – 8x8, 9x9, or 9x13
Ingredients Directions
– 3⁄4 cup plus 2 tablespoons granulated sugar
– 1 cup self-rising flour
– 1⁄4 cup plus 1⁄4 cup (1 stick) butter, melted – 1 (28 oz) can sliced peaches, undrained
• Preheat the oven to 350°.
• In a medium size mixing bowl, coarsely mix 3⁄4 cup of the sugar, the flour, and 1⁄4 cup of the melted butter together.
• Sprinkle about one-third of this mixture to the bottom of a baking dish.
• Add the peaches with the juice on top of mixture. (If juice from the peaches does not cover the peaches, add a small amount of water to cover the peaches. Too little liquid will make the cobble dry. Too much liquid will make it soupy.)
• Top the peaches with the remaining sugar/flour mixture.
• Sprinkle the top with the remaining 2 tablespoons of sugar and the remaining 1⁄4 cup melted butter.
• Bake for 30-40 mins or until brown and bubbly. Serve hot.
HINT: Fresh peaches can be used. When using fresh peaches, peel and slice them, sprinkling the slices with an additional 1⁄2 cup sugar. Refrigerate them for 2-3 hours before using. Yields: 6-8 Servings
  43
 ]]></page><page Index="47" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  Julia’s Pumpkin Pie
by Richard Chiappone
Ingredients
– 1 9” Pastry Shell (unbaked) (Pillsbury type is fine)
– 1 16oz can of pumpkin filling “or”
2 cups fresh cooked pumpkin (mashed well) (can is more accurate according to Uncle Charlie...friggin’ expert he
thinks he is...)
– 1 14oz can of “Eagle” brand sweetened condensed milk (NOT Evaporated Milk) I learned that one the hard way...don’t ask!
– 2 Eggs
– 1 tsp ground cinnamon
– 1⁄2 tsp ground ginger
– 1⁄2 tsp ground nutmeg
– 1⁄2 tsp salt
– Optional: Fresh Whipped Cream
Directions
• Preheat oven to 425 degrees
• In a large mixing bowl, combine all ingredients (except pastry shell, of course!) and mix well.
• Lightly spray pie dish or tin with cooking spray (“I said lightly, not grease it up!”...hey her words, not mine...)
• Press pastry shell into the 9” pie dish or tin
• Place into the 425 degree oven for 15 mins
• Reduce heat after 15 mins to 350 degrees and bake an additional 35-40 mins (pie crust should begin to turn brown)
• Once brown, insert a knife (“What’s the matter with you?!!! Not a toothpick or you’ll burn your fingers and get germs on my pie!”...again, her words, not mine...) into 1” from the edge of the pie (yup, you read correctly)
• When it comes out clean, pie is done.
• Cool and serve with Fresh Whipped Cream in a bowl on the side.
 44
  ]]></page><page Index="48" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Old & Brown Chocolate Chip Cookies by William Campbell
 My Son has always loved Chocolate Chip Cookies and many years ago I was a big fan of Alton Brown’s TV Show “Good Eats”. Alton had a recipe for really Chewy Chocolate Chip cookies
so I gave it a try. When my Son saw me making cookies he asked what kind I was making and I responded with, “Alton Browns Chocolate Chip Cookies”. My Son basically devoured them in a few days after which he asked if I would make more of the “Old & Brown Chocolate Chip Cookies”. You see, he misunderstood what
I called them originally. Over
the past 14 years my Son has been requesting “Old & Brown Chocolate Chip Cookies” each and every December!!
Active Time: 20 minutes Directions
Total Time: 1 hour & 50 minutes Yield: 2 Dozen Cookies
Ingredients
– 8 ounces unsalted butter (2 sticks) – 12 ounces bread flour (2 1/4 cups) – 1 teaspoon kosher salt
– 1 teaspoon baking soda
– 2 ounces granulated sugar (1/4 cup) – 8 ounces light brown sugar
(1/4 cup + 1 cup)
– 1 large egg
– 1 large egg yolk
– 1 ounce whole milk (2 tablespoons)
– 1 1/2 teaspoons vanilla extract
– 12 ounces semisweet chocolate chips
• Heat oven to 375°F and place the racks in the top third and bottom third of
the oven. Line 4 half-sheet pans with parchment paper and set aside.
• Melt the butter in a 2-quart saucepan over low heat. Set aside to cool slightly.
• Sift together the flour, salt, and baking soda onto a paper plate.
• Pour the butter into the bowl of your stand mixer. Add the sugars and beat with the paddle attachment on medium speed for 2 minutes.
• Meanwhile in a separate bowl, whisk together the whole egg, egg yolk, milk, and vanilla extract.
• Slow the mixer to “stir” and slowly work the egg mixture into the butter and sugar. Mix until thoroughly combined, about 30 seconds.
 45
 ]]></page><page Index="49" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[   • Using the paper plate as a slide, gradually integrate the dry ingredients, stopping a few times to scrape down the side of the bowl with a rubber spatula. Once the flour is worked in, add the chocolate chips. Chill the dough for 1 hour.
• Scoop the dough into 1 1/2-ounce portions and place on the half-sheet pans, 6 cookies per sheet.
• Bake two sheets at a time for 15 minutes, rotating pans halfway through baking.
• Remove from the oven, slide the parchment with the cookies onto a cooling rack, and wait at least
5 minutes before devouring.
46
   ]]></page><page Index="50" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  Brazilian Brigadeiro
by Stephany Ferreira
When my mother and I moved to America we left everything behind and the one thing that made us feel like we were close to home was this one recipe that our family would always make together. So when we felt sad or alone my mother and I would open up our family cookbook and make this recipe. I won’t lie to you this recipe is a labor of love although it might not seem like it, I promise you that your family will enjoy it.
 Ingredients Directions
•
•
•
•
Reserve, letting it cool to room temperature.
In a plate or bowl, spread your sprinkles.
Once the brigadeiro is cool, grease your hands with butter and roll the brigadeiros into little balls.(In Brazil we usually use half a tablespoon as measurement, but you can make your balls as big or small as you’d like!).
Roll the brigadeiro balls into the sprinkles and place them in paper/foil candy cups.
– 1 (14oz) can sweet condensed milk
– 4 Tbsp cocoa powder, sifted
– 2 Tbsp butter, plus more for rolling balls
– A pinch of salt
– Good quality chocolate sprinkles (or any other type of sprinkles you like)
• In a small sauce pan mix the sweet condensed milk, the cocoa powder, the salt and the butter.
• Bring the sauce pan to the stove and heat it over medium-low heat.
• Cook it, mixing constantly (this is important, otherwise it will burn!) until it thickens. A way to know is to run your wooden spoon (or spatula) in the middle of the mixture. If it takes a while for the mixture to move, then your brigadeiro is ready!
 47
 ]]></page><page Index="51" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  Dutch Apple Cheesecake by Kayla Schill
It reminds me of fall, no matter Directions
  what time of year it is and
it’s the easiest cheesecake to make or adapt with a different fruit topping.
Ingredients
– 1⁄4 C unsalted butter
– 1 1⁄2 C graham cracker crumbs
– 1 can sweetened condensed milk
– 1 C sour cream
– 1⁄4 C lemon juice
– 21 oz apple pie filling
Optional
– 1⁄4 C chopped walnuts
– 1⁄2 t cinnamon
• Preheat oven to 350 degrees Fahrenheit
• In a 1.5 qt baking dish, melt butter and sprinkle in graham cracker crumbs and press in dish • Mix condensed milk, sour cream, and lemon juice and spread over crumbs
• Spoon the pie filling on top of the milk filling
• Bake 25 to 30 min or until set
• Cool slightly
Optional: mix nuts and cinnamon and sprinkle on top before serving
 48
  ]]></page><page Index="52" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Polish Babcia’s Apple Pie by Jessica Miranda
    This tart apple pie recipe
was taught to me by my Polish
Crust
– 2 1⁄2 cups all-purpose flour
– 1 tsp salt
– 3 tsp sugar
– 2 sticks of unsalted butter (cut into 1⁄2 inch cubes)
– 6-8 tbsp cold water
– 1 egg
Filling
– 10-12 medium Honeycrisp apples (may need more depending on how much filling you want)
– 2-3 tsp Cinnamon or to liking – 2-3 tsp Sugar or to liking
To make the dough
• In large bowl, combine flour, salt and sugar, and mix to combine
• Add butter 1⁄2 stick at a time and
work the cold butter into the flour mixture. Should get a crumbly texture. Do not over work, we do not want the butter to melt.
• Slowly at 1 tbsp of cold water at time until it forms into dough.
• Wrap and refrigerate for at least 1 hour.
To make the filling
• Peel the apples
• Using a grater, grate all the apples
• Take the grated apple and squeeze as much juice out of them as possible. You want to make them dry.
• Place in another bowl. Continue until all the apple pulp has been squeezed (NOTE: you can drink the juice, it is delicious)
• Add the cinnamon and sugar to the apples and mix
grandmother, it was the first dessert I ever attempted to make on my own and it turns
out great every time. Since she has passed many years ago, my family remembers it as her apple pie and it is our favorite holiday dessert. It is very different than American apple pie.
  49
 ]]></page><page Index="53" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[   Assemble the pie
• Remove the dough from the fridge and separate it into 2 portions
• Roll the dough out so that it fits the size of the pie plate selected. Should have 1 for the top and 1 for the bottom
• Place the bottom pie crust into the pie plate. Using a fork prick the dough
• Take the grated apples and place it in the pie plate on top of the bottom crust
• You want to mound the apples so that it creates a dome in the pie plate
• Place the other rolled out pie dough on top.
• Remove the excess dough around the sides and pinch the two pie crusts together using a fork
• Again, using a fork prick the top pie crust
• In a small bowl whisk the egg and use it as a wash over the top of the pie
• Bake at 425F for 15 min, reduce heat to 350F and bake for 35-45 min
• Best enjoyed warm
50
   ]]></page><page Index="54" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[    Bacon Coffee Cake by Laura Shelden
 My mother would make this recipe around the holidays each year. It has been in my family for generations and is an amazing breakfast or snack with coffee or tea. Also, BACON!
Ingredients Directions
51
– 3 Cups Flour
– 3 Tsp Baking Soda
– 1⁄2 Cup Granulated Sugar
– 1 Cup Brown Sugar (packed) – 2 Tsp Cinnamon
– 1⁄2 Tsp Salt
– 1 Cup Cold Bacon Grease
– 2 Eggs
– 1 Cup Milk
• Sift dry ingredients together.
• Cut in bacon grease using a pastry blender and blend until crumbly.
• Remove 1⁄2 to 3⁄4 cup of this mixture and set aside.
• To the rest add the eggs & milk.
• Pour into two 8-9 inch greased pans.
• Top with reserved mixture and bake at 350 degrees for 25 minutes.
 ]]></page><page Index="55" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Leche Flan by Raymond Swain
This is a traditional Filipino Directions
Dessert that is served at every holiday or gathering. This was one of my favorites growing up. It’s based of Creme Brulee but in my opinion is a lot easier to make.
Ingredients
– Dozen Egg Yolks
– 1 16oz Can Evaporated Milk
– 1 14oz Can Sweeten Condensed Milk
– 1 TSP Vanilla Extract
– 1 Cup Sugar
– 2 TBSP Water
• In small pot mix sugar and water heat on low heat until sugar is completely melted and caramelized. Pour this mixture into your mold and let harden a bit does not need to be solid. (use loaf tin or 9x9 pan if you do not have brulee molds)
• Mix Egg yolks, Evaporated
Milk, Sweeten Condensed Milk, Vanilla extra. Do not stir heavily to avoid creating bubbles.
• Run mixture through sieve and pour into mold. Cover mold with Aluminum Foil
• Place molds in water bath and bake in oven at 375F for 50 minutes – 1 hour or until toothpick comes out clean.
• Remove from oven allow to
cool. To serve turn flan over
in serving plate so caramel is on top.
 52
    ]]></page><page Index="56" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Mango Float by Ralph-Jason Comia
This is a dessert that my mom and her mom made every year around
 the holidays. It doesn’t require a lot tradition that I’d like to share.
Ingredients
to make, and it is a family Directions
• Drizzle the layer with the Cream/ Condensed milk mixture. Make sure it is covered by a light coat.
• Repeat to the number of layers desired. 3-5 layers suggested.
• For the top layer, cover with a layer
of graham crackers. Pour the cream mixture to coat the top and cover with sliced mangoes/peaches. Sprinkle graham crumbs to finish.
• Cover the tray, and place in freezer for 2-4 hours or overnight. Best served chilled to frozen.
– 3-4 cans Table Cream •
In a large bowl, mix 3-4-parts Table Cream to 1-part Condensed Milk.
– 1 can Condensed Milk
– Graham Crackers
– Canned Mangoes or Peaches (sliced)
• Prepare the sliced fruits: If the slices in the can are thick, then slice them in half. Drain out all of the syrup.
• In a rectangular tray or container, such as a baking loaf pan, begin the layering process:
• Start with covering the bottom with a layer of graham crackers. It does not need to be perfect, and you
can always break up the crackers to fit the gaps. Set aside all crumbs created in this process.
• Cover the graham crackers with the sliced peaches or mangoes, about half an inch apart each slice.
 53
 ]]></page><page Index="57" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[   54
  ]]></page><page Index="58" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[             55
  ]]></page><page Index="59" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Cocktails
56
]]></page><page Index="60" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Margie’s Cranberry Mule by Margaret Carles-Tufano
This drink is delicious and festive. Also, cranberry juice is rich in antioxidants and offers a good source of vitamins C and E.
Why not try this drink for a mood boost and a health boost (in moderation, of course)? Want to make it kid friendly? Just omit the vodka/rum. Of course, you can use the proposed portions as a suggestion to start!
Ingredients
– Ice ice baby
– 1 part vodka or dark rum
– 1 part cranberry juice cocktail
– 2 parts ginger beer
– 1 squeeze of lime
– A nice glass, copper mule mug, or to-go thermos if you will be sitting in holiday traffic
Directions
• Pour vodka/rum, cranberry juice cocktail, beer and lime juice in your vessel of choice filled with ice. Stir to combine.
• Garnish with lime wedges and fresh cranberries, if desired.
  57
 ]]></page><page Index="61" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  Egg Nog
by Michael VanStory
Ingredients
– 4 Egg yokes
– 1⁄2 lb granulated sugar
– 1 quart of milk
– 1/5 Old Duram Rye Whiskey
– 1 cup Jamaca Rum
– Powdered Sugar
Directions
• Beat egg yokes and sugar until good and creamy
• Add milk and whiskey and rum until combined
• Whip egg whites and powdered sugar
• Fold into the milk and whiskey mix
   58
  ]]></page><page Index="62" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[      59
  ]]></page></pages></Search>